FAYE ZHANG

Email: zhan1518@umn.edu Tel: 612-5161274 Address: 1512 Vista Club Circle, Apt 202, Santa Clara, CA, 95054

Please check out my portfolio! https://intelj711.github.io/allAboutMe/allAboutMe.html

I'm expecting a Front End/Full Stack engineer position with this portfolio. Even I'm an engineer at hardware company, I'm doing software development from 3 years ago all the way till now. I picked up different languages based on project needs, fast and got significant grow in short time. I've been keeping working on JAVA API development for 2 years at my current company.

PROFICIENCIES

- Front-End: HTML5/CSS3/Javascript, ES6, React-Redux, JQuery, Bootstrap, Ajax
- Back- End: Node JS, Express, MongoDB, RESTful API, Java
- Knowledge of: Sementic-UI, Sass, AngularJS, Firebase, etc

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Electrical Engineering Jul, 2010 – May, 2012 Master of Science Electrical Engineering SEP, 2012 – May, 2014 University of Minnesota-twin cities

University of Minnesota-twin cities

EXPERIENCE

SR. RELIABILITY SOFTWARE ENGINEER (SAN JOSE, CA)

Jan, 2015 - Present

- SK Hynix Memory Solution. System Department.
- Design, develop, optimize and execute test plans and regression test cases from functional specs of enterprise SSD product.
- Work with team to implement reliability test by creating JAVA API to Neosom chamber:
 - o Implement SATA and NVMe interface standard commands, SKHMS vendor unique commands and different workload loop from JAVA level based on Neosom API.
 - **o** Support hardware and firmware failure analysis on drive level by collecting all detailed log and tracking data.
 - Reliability analysis includes: Performance across different workload, endurance, UECC, read disturb, power state, temperature swing, and other test cases added according to customer spec, industry common spec and FW and HW debugging purpose.
 - Parse and process data by creating Python script and JMP.
 - **o** Be gate keeper of product release based on the result of reliability test of 1-day baseline, 1-week mix workload test with temperature condition changing and voltage margin, and 6-week stress RDT.
- Be responsible of data collecting and reviewing of the mass qualify of Pearl product (SATA) and provided weekly report to customer. Created **Python** and **PowerShell** automation script for data parsing and analyzing. Identifying, analyzing, and documenting any defects discovered during testing. Worked with FW or HW engineer on bugs fixing. Supported further discussion with customer through the whole product mass quality.
- Created LUA automation script to measure commands latency and work with FW engineer to get improvement and to meet spec requirement.

VALIDATION ENGINEER INTERN (SAN JOSE, CA)

Jan, 2014 - Oct. 2014

- **HGST, a West Digital Company.** Preamp Technology & Characterization Team. Validated multichannel front-end preamp performance and characterization on chip level and HDD level.
- Created **TCL** automation script with GUI to measure chip power consumption while toning through multiple register settings. Worked with validation engineer in Fujisawa head quarter on data review.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN (PLYMOUTH. MN)

MAY, 2013 – Aug. 2013

- Nonin Medical. Firmware Team.
- Worked on development of automation of C++ script to support test of firmware functionality and validate the accuracy of hardware prototypes for non-invasive medical devices.